Muhammad Mutahar Aslam

Front End Developer

I have around +6 years of experience in web-based technologies. I've working experience in agile/scrum environments. Always thirsty to dive into new technologies, currently working as a Frontend Engineer in Different technologies like React/React-native Angular. I'm determined to learn & work on new technologies. A good team player with excellent interpersonal/communication skills.

mutaharaslam@gmail.com

Lahore, Pakistan

github.com/Mutaharaslam



+92 314 3366119

in linkedin.com/in/muhammad-mutahar-aslam-2a4041a8

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Retailo Technologies

02/2022 - Present

Lahore, Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Maintaining front-end applications developed in React/RN.
- Contributing to a Design System of React Native to reuse its components across the Company-wide RN Applications.

Senior User Interface Engineer NextBridge Ltd

07/2021 - 02/2022

Lahore. Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Ionic React/Angular Native mobile and Web Apps.
- Conversion of mocks/wireframes to User interface using Ionic.
- Collaborated with business analysts to refine requirements.

Software Engineer

MobileLive

12/2017 - 07/2021

Lahore, Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Maintained front-end applications developed in React and Angular.
- Collaborated with business analysts to refine requirements and
- Conducted internal trainings to onboard UI engineers.
- UI/UX development, Mobile & Cross Browser Compatibility.
- Assisted other team members and stakeholders at offshore & onshore regarding technical matters.

Media Executive - Operations PlanOnemedia

01/2017 - 09/2017

Lahore, Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Social Media Advertisement, Photoshop, UI/UX, WordPress.
- Campaign using Social media and Website for a Movie "Chain Ave Na".
- Worked on dawnfrozenfoods.com.

Internship as Wordpress & UI Developer **Total Software Services**

01/2016 - 08/2016

Arfa IT Park, Lahore, Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Web Apps using WordPress & Theme/Plugin Customisation.
- Conversion of PSD to HTML/CSS/JS.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Software Engineering Government College University, Faisalabad

06/2012 - 06/2016 Faisalabad, Pakistan

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Fido My Account (03/2018 - 03/2020) 3

Worked as a UI/UX developer in the team of stream and optimizations for production applications, my responsibilities were to build new pages and integrate into an existing website, this web-app belongs to one of the biggest telecommunication company in Canada.

rogers.com <a>C

- Worked on some UI projects, E.g. Android-Homepage (also on Fido), Rio project.

UXPLORE (angular) 🗷

- Setup Boiler plate for UI
- Made some inner pages with using Angular
- Pixel perfect/ Cross browser Compatible

Intellija Angular ERP Application

- An ERP application based on AG-Grid, Angular and GraphQL
- Developed the inner pages with using Ag-grid
- Implement the APIs with GraphQL

Freedom Mobile

- Worked on the inner pages of the website to meat Web Accessibility Standards.

Friday Design System From Scratch 🗷

- A general Design System based on static components
- Using CSS Custom Properties + Theming with pure css
- Prettier/Stylint/Cross Browsing/web pack Compatible
- Setup Boiler plate for UI

mobilelive.ca (React) 🗷

- Worked on UI Components to add new Modules/Pages.
- pixel perfection, Cross browser Compatibility.

Hybrid Apps with Ionic (07/2021 - Present)

- Developing The User Interface in Ionic angular/React
- Cross Browser Compatibility Testing on Native Platforms
- Interacting with Clients for feedbacks and feasibility of the Apps

Migration of HubSpot to WordPress &

- Migration of all the blogs, whitePapers, Case Studies, News and Infographics to WordPress
- Implementation of WordPress forms to Pardot Salesforce
- Designed the structure of WordPress for all the incoming Data from HubSpot

LANGUAGES

HRDH Full Professional Proficiency English

Professional Working Proficiency